(The tassel crowns the knight.
The sword is snow white.)
(In the silver saddle,
he rides like a shooting star.)
(He kills a man within ten steps.
Invincible he is all the way ahead.)
(He would leave once it's done.
No trace of him is to be found.)
=Sword Snow Stride= (Season 1)
=Episode 13=
Who is that?
All right.
Old fellow.
Your hearing gets better!
Old brother.
It's you.
Yeah, I'm here.
It's the end of the year now.
This government
distributed
some rice
to us.
I brought some here
to surprise you.
Well,
I can escape your eyes,
but I can't escape your ears.
I was just
talking about you with that boy.
Um.
If you came a little earlier,
you would be able to meet him.
Um.
Old brother.
You work in the government.
Just give him a hand
if you can.
Well,
he doesn't need my help.
I beg you.
Please.
All right.
Let's not talk about him.
Well,
it's the end of the year.
Tell me
if there is anything you want
or you want to do.
I have a regret,
but you can't
help me.
Ah?
Tell me about it.
My only regret
in this life
is that I didn't
take a look at General Xu.
At first, the cavalry
only had 600 soldiers.
Now the world is at peace.
I didn't even have a word
with General Xu.
What a pity is that!
Xu Xiao
is an old man with a white beard now.
Don't call General Xu by his name!
All right.
Don't get excited.
What's there to be mad about?
Come on. Sit down.
Sit down first.
The cavalryman of the lowest rank
from the 18th Laozi Battalion
and Yugu Battalion
of Jinzhou
greets General Xu.
Why are you so sure
that I'm Xu Xiao?
After the battle
where I got my eyes hurt,
you came to see the wounded.
You held my hand
and told me
that I must stay alive.
Although I couldn't see,
I've remembered
your hands for a lifetime.
Old brother, get up.
Come on.
Sit down.
General Xu.
If you don't mind me asking,
is that boy Xu your...?
He's my son.
Xu Fengnian.
Congratulations to General Xu.
You and the Consort
gave birth to a good son.
I'm content with
my life now.
I have no regrets anymore.
General Xu.
I have one more question.
How many of those old brothers
are still alive?
As long as the flag
of the army of North Liang
doesn't fall,
they are still there.
Then I'll tell them
that there is an inheritor
of North Liang.
This flag
will never fall.
Are you still reading on New Year's Eve?
The new year will come anyway
no matter what you do.
It's such a happy day.
Don't be so philosophical.
Where's Grandpa Wei?
He's sleeping on the second floor.
Good.
Let's drink.
In previous years, I could see
snow scenes during the New Year.
This year,
I can only have some wine.
Come on.
How do you spend the New Year
in North Mang?
Where there are people,
it's all basically the same.
The same people spend the same New Year.
But they have to
fight with each other to death.
People and people fight.
Village and village fight.
Town and town fight.
How can the state be an exception?
Well said.
♪ The millions of people in North Liang ♪
♪ How many of them end up dead in armor ♪
Listen.
♪ Drink down feat and fame ♪
It's the Requiem for the Phantom
of North Liang.
My second sister wrote the lyrics.
I composed the music.
At the end of each year,
more than 30 musicians
and 160 dancers
play music and dance in the city.
If you go out now,
you can see the lights
brighten the night.
♪ The earth mixed with snow
and the hot stove ♪
I'll just listen.
♪ The white hands and the slim waist ♪
♪ One hundred thousand crossbows ♪
♪ Almost cover the sky ♪
The lyrics are good,
but the music is normal.
♪ Millions of fellows ♪
♪ Can't see the way back home ♪
That's also what my second sister said.
Maybe you two will get along.
♪ Don't say
that all heroes fall into a trap ♪
♪ Young ladies ♪
♪ Don't hide your feelings of love ♪
I heard that you are going
to leave again.
Yes.
I'll go to Wudi City.
♪ Come come come ♪
♪ Who is playing the Beauty Drum ♪
♪ Who is mending the sky with one hand ♪
♪ Come come come ♪
♪ Who will compete with me ♪
I lend them to you.
I'll need them back.
Both of them?
All right.
It's worth it to drink with you.
♪ One hundred thousand crossbows ♪
♪ Almost cover the sky ♪
♪ Millions of fellows ♪
♪ Can't see the way back home ♪
♪ Good men ♪
♪ Don't say
that all heroes fall into a trap ♪
♪ Young ladies ♪
♪ Don't hide your feelings of love ♪
♪ Come come come ♪
♪ Who is playing the Beauty Drum ♪
♪ Who is mending the sky with one hand ♪
♪ Come come come ♪
♪ Who will compete with me ♪
The moods get depressed
when I drink alone.
I'll find someone else.
Thank you.
You are not from here.
A book stealer!
Do you want wine?
Save me a mouthful.
You really saved me a mouthful.
Listen.
These are not secret scriptures.
The secret scriptures are up there.
Let's go.
I'll take you to find them.
Come on.
Let's go.
Be gentle.
White Fox is sleeping.
Don't wake her up.
And also,
you don't take...
Don't take secret scriptures.
Secret scriptures are hard to sell.
The antiques and precious stones
are on the fourth floor.
Those things are valuable.
I mean, White Fox is sleeping.
Should I stay by her side?
You have a point.
I need to watch her.
Don't let her throw up on my clothes.
I'm leaving.
Don't take too much.
Don't be too greedy.
It's hard to believe
you are Xu Xiao's son.
Interesting.
What did you say?
What are you doing?
You're awake.
Since you are awake,
I'll go back.
Do you need me to send you back?
No need.
No matter how drunk I am,
I can still find
my way back home.
Xu Fengnian!
What are you doing in my room?
This is my room!
It's okay.
I got drunk last night
and went into the wrong room.
Don't worry.
I'll explain it to everyone.
Don't say anything!
Ah?
Don't say anything.
I'll tell everyone it's me...
Get out!
You are too loud.
They must have heard you.
Don't you need me to explain it?
- Get out now!
- Let me
put on my shoes.
(The following spring)
(Mansion of Lord of North Liang)
My Lord.
Everything is ready.
We can leave anytime.
As you required,
Ning Emei
will lead
a cavalry of 100 soldiers
of Fengzi Battalion
to go with you.
You will see them
after you set off.
Qingniao
will drive the carriage for you.
From now on,
you have to keep it in mind
every word I said.
My Lord.
- Your Highness.
- Um.
Wei Shuyang.
My Lord.
Wei Shuyang
is learned and capable,
especially in terms of
martial arts.
You should
rely on him more.
Grandpa Wei, thank you.
Your Highness, you're welcome.
Her name is Shu Xiu.
You met her before.
She knows
how the world of martial arts works.
You can ask her
in case of any special circumstances.
You can ask me anything.
Be careful.
Um.
Why is there no one by that carriage?
The carriage driver will come soon.
What are you doing inside?
I'll stay with Jiang Ni
no matter where she goes.
That's absurd!
Jiang Ni won't come with me.
You are...
Which carriage will take me?
This one!
You planned this?
Yes.
I'm leaving for
the world of martial arts.
Why should I take Jiang Ni?
You need
someone
to take care of you
on the road.
There are so many maids.
Why did you pick Jiang Ni?
If you leave Jiang Ni in the mansion,
what if
your second sister's subordinates
try to hurt her again?
That's the only reason?
I have to bother you
to take care of Fengnian
during this trip!
Hey!
Don't smear my carriage!
Who is that person?
The monster
who was locked
under the Tingchao Pavilion.
By the way,
there is one thing
you must keep in mind.
Never give him a sword.
What kind of sword?
All kinds of swords.
What about a wooden sword?
Not even a wooden sword!
Give him a name at least.
Eh.
The other carriage driver is here.
Great Sword,
Lyu Qiantang.
You're not Lyu Qiantang!
Aren't you Lin
who tried to assassinate me?
I'm Lyu Qiantang.
Greetings to Your Highness.
Your voice doesn't even change!
Don't you lie to me!
(Lyu Qiantang, retainer)
I'm Lyu Qiantang.
Greetings to Your Highness.
What is going on now?
Your first stop is Qingzhou.
The Lin family in Qingzhou
has been cornered
by the Lord of Jing'an.
It will do you no harm
to let him come with you.
You forced him to yield?
He must yield
if he wants to save the Lin family.
A centipede does not topple over
even when dead.
The Lin family is still lingering on
in Qingzhou.
If you don't want it to perish,
don't forget
what I told you.
Yes.
How many things have you planned?
Don't worry.
With that old man by your side,
even the world is turned upside down,
he will keep you safe.
Who is that old man?
He will tell you
when he wants.
After you leave,
I will head for the capital.
I'll be in the court, and you'll be
in the world of martial arts.
Only we join forces,
can we preserve
the hereditary system in North Liang.
Um.
Be careful on the road.
Go now.
How much more
have you planned along the way?
We hit the road
and embrace whatever comes.
Set off.
You got a letter from North Liang?
What happened?
None of your business.
Don't say that.
You and I
will be a family one day.
Your business is my business.
Hongchi?
You have the ancient sword.
Get away.
It's human nature
for men and women to fall in love.
I'm the only one
who is good enough for you
in Shangyin Academy.
Eh?
You should think about it.
Why are you here in person?
Xu Fengnian
is going to leave North Liang.
Oh?
Didn't he just go back
from a three-year tour?
It's not secretive this time.
He is traceable.
He is bold indeed.
But,
what does it have to do with me
that he's gonna leave North Liang?
Kill him.
Is it the order of the court?
No.
Master.
I have no grievances against him,
and he might become
my brother-in-law one day.
If I kill him,
what's in it for me?
If he dies,
North Liang will be in chaos,
and the world will be in chaos.
Only when the world is in chaos,
can you have a chance to stand out.
In this case,
it's kind of interesting
to kill my brother-in-law.
Without the imperial order,
I can't do it myself.
I can only give you some helpers.
(Han Diaosi, the Eunuch Chief of Liyang)
The Fengzi Battalion's cavalry
of 100 soldiers
is waiting ahead.
I thought you would leave me
and head for Mount Longhu
once you are outside Lingzhou.
The military order has been issued.
The Fengzi Battalion
will escort you to the east.
You just escort me
when the order says so?
Of course.
Orders are orders.
Aren't you going
to get Huangman'er back?
That's not on the military order.
After we get to Mount Longhu,
I'll leave the team
and rescue Young Master Longxiang
on my own.
Is the cavalry of Fengzi Battalion
waiting ahead on the main road?
Not on the main road.
They are waiting in the woods.
Why?
To avoid disturbing the people
when there is no military order.
Don't you know it?
Then I have to trouble you
to bring them here.
Please stay, Your Highness.
Iron Cavalry.
You are Dian Xiongchu.
(Dian Xiongchu, General of Iron Cavalry)
Please wait a moment, Your Highness.
Our general wants
to see you off in person.
I remember you are
Chen Zhibao's subordinate.
Please wait at your ease.
What if I don't want to wait?
You didn't even tell me
that you are leaving.
I'm willing to be at your service,
holding your whip and following
your stirrups, Your Highness.
Dian.
Make way.
General Chu.
I don't think your crossbow
can't shoot through the iron armor
of the Iron Cavalry.
Do you wanna try it?
Young Master Xu is leaving.
Iron Cavalry, make way now!
General Chen asked
Young Master Xu to wait.
The title of the army
of North Liang is Xu,
not Chen.
General Ning.
Are you really willing to serve him?
I'm asking you to make way.
You can try to charge
if you dare.
Are you done?
Who can afford the charge
of infighting within North Liang?
I'll give you one last chance.
Make way.
Get ready to charge!
Raise your bow!
Aren't you supposed
to protect Xu Fengnian?
I'll go out
when he is dying.
There are battle-hardened
elite soldiers out there.
How many can you stop by yourself?
Thousands of soldiers
are just easy prey to me.
Everyone can brag.
Chen Zhibao.
Be careful.
Don't you know
what will happen if one of my men
releases the arrow?
I just left Lingzhou
and you caught up with me in a hurry.
Are you so eager to kill me?
Dian Xiongchu!
General.
Dian Xiongchu can escort you
to the east.
I don't think
we are that close.
You can't die now
for North Liang's sake.
Why don't you die first
for North Liang's sake?
It's none of your business.
Young Master Xu's business
is my business.
Stop fighting.
I refuse to leave with Iron Cavalry.
Ning Emei's Fengzi Battalion is enough.
He always hates you.
I don't think he will try his best
to protect you.
Well, do you and Dian Xiongchu
appreciate me?
With my order,
Dian Xiongchu will use his life
to protect you.
No need.
Think it through.
It's not safe
to leave North Liang.
Ning Emei.
Yes!
Before we get to Mount Longhu,
can you protect my life?
With the military order,
as long as there is one soldier alive
in Fengzi Battalion,
you will be fine.
Compared with you,
I trust him more.
Iron Cavalry. Return to the camp.
The heavily armored cavalry left.
Are you worried about that boy?
Who is worried about him?
I'm worried about myself.
If the cavalry starts to fight,
you will protect Xu Fengnian.
What about me?
I've decided to take over North Liang.
You are not qualified.
I leave this time
to win myself the heirship.
None of this matters.
You must have three things
before you take over North Liang.
One,
a cruel heart.
Two,
a scheming mind.
Three,
connections.
You are not good enough
at any of them.
That's basically what Xu Xiao said.
Can there be something new?
What about you?
Are you good enough at
these three things?
He is alone.
How about we...
I kind of appreciate him.
There is something about that guy.
That's why you can't keep him.
Don't mess around.
Your Highness.
You shouldn't have told him
about the heirship.
You can't hide things like that.
Telling it now
can help North Liang
and the capital
prepare in advance.
Go back.
I'll escort you to leave North Liang.
Xu Xiao will leave for the capital soon.
You can protect him at that time.
Really?
It's settled.
I got it.
Be careful, Your Highness.
Let's set off.
What are you looking at?
You have good qualifications.
Do you want to learn
something useful from me?
No.
Why not?
The fools
who wanted to be my apprentices before
could line up for North Liang
to the East Sea.
Only fools wanted
to be your apprentices?
Do you know who I am?
Why should I care?
You have a point.
I almost forgot
who I am.
Who else would remember Mumaniu?
This one is really big...
You finally got one!
But you let it escape!
You tried to kill me
last time when we met.
Now you are my guard.
You'll get used to it.
I remember
it wasn't this sword last time.
This sword
is called Chixia.
Grand Commander gave it to me.
You are a scholar.
Scholars can also use swords.
Scholars are unpredictable.
Maybe you will
stab me with a sword again one day.
Only when you are alive,
Grand Commander will give my family
the last chance to live.
How is the Lin family now?
The mansion has been ransacked
by the Lord of Jing'an.
Then you should beg the Lord of Jing'an.
What's the use to turn to Xu Xiao?
You don't know
how horrible your father is.
Even he changed his name,
his surname will always be Lin.
What are you trying to say?
There is a danger
of keeping such a person by your side.
I have looked into his eyes.
He can even give up his life.
It won't do any difference
whether I kill him or not.
He is dead inside.
I'll keep an eye on him
for you, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Why don't you go inside?
I'll keep watch before midnight.
No need.
The Fengzi Battalion camped near us.
It's safe.
It's better not
to trust others with our lives.
Who will guard here after the midnight?
Um.
We have left Lingzhou.
I know.
Now that we are out of North Liang,
we have a chance now.
What chance?
To run away.
Where?
Anywhere is better than here.
Have you ever thought about
why Xu Xiao picked you
to follow Xu Fengnian in this trip?
What's the worst that can happen to you?
I die.
Yeah.
Maybe you will die.
Xu Xiao killed so many people.
Why does he keep me alive?
The Princess of Chu's life
is still quite useful
at the crucial moment.
He wants to kill you?
Not to kill me,
but to change my life for something.
Where's Jiang Ni?
Where are you from?
You have to do something about it.
I'm reading now.
What's the use of reading?
Can you acquire martial arts
in such a short time?
I charge for reading.
I can get seven strings of pennies
after I read this book.
How can you still
think about making money
at this time?
You know
the funeral custom in Chu
is complicated.
A funeral will cost a lot.
I've been thinking
that I have no relatives and no family,
and my state fell.
If I don't even
have a funeral after I die,
won't it be too pitiful?
You want to make money
to...
To hold myself a funeral.
But why are you
trying to kill Xu Fengnian?
You hate the Xu family?
No.
What else could it be?
Because...
His Highness wants to see you.
It's finally time to read.
I'll go with you.
He only wants to see Jiang Ni.
I put my money box in the tent.
I'll guard it for you.
Do you need me to read?
Yes.
Not this one.
Get those books in the carriage.
But I've been reading it for days.
It doesn't count
if you didn't read it to me.
One penny for each word.
I'll pay you after you finish it.
Don't you think it smells bad?
Yes.
I'm kind of uncomfortable
after staying in the carriage all day.
There is hot water by the bonfire.
Wash your hands and feet by yourself.
Me?
Don't come back until you are clean!
Which one?
Read this one first.
Compendium of Swords.
(The Prologue of Compendium of Swords)
Sword is the head of all weapons.
It's made to kill.
At the beginning of everything,
there was gold falling from the sky.
An ancient immortal got it
and refined it into steel.
That was the first sword in the world.
It was the gathering of water and fire,
the mixture of Yin and Yang,
somewhere in between
rigidity and softness.
Divide the mountains with strength.
Heaven and earth perished.
The sword works by impaling bodies.
The so-called Dancing Sleeves
Whisking the Pear Blossoms,
the Flying Snow,
the Fleeing Time,
the Horse Back,
are all the manifestations
of the skills.
The skills can be taught easily,
but the art of martial arts
is unspeakable.
10, 15.
20, 25.
30.
Keep reading.
Let me count how many words I've read.
You can count together after you finish.
55.
60.
65.
70, 75.
80, 85.
90, 95.
100 pennies for 100 words.
There are 97 words.
Where are the three more?
Just three more words!
Why are you so stingy?
I'm the one who pays the money.
Fine, 97!
I'll keep reading.
Being cautious leads to weakness.
The meaning is deep.
The art of martial arts
has different styles
and can be divided into Yin and Yang.
Cultivate the spirit and be righteous.
The internal force will come into being.
Breathe in and breathe out
in a solid way.
There is no boundary.
All crap!
This book can mislead learners.
It's full of absurdity.
Do you know this book?
It's Compendium of Swords.
When Du Sicong wrote this book,
he wanted to put aside the skills
and seek for the art of swordsmanship.
Unfortunately, he was inadequate
and the book is biased.
I scolded him
when he was writing the book.
It's a pity
that he still went the wrong way.
Du Sicong who wrote
the Compendium of Swords
was scolded by you?
He came to me for advice
and stood in the snow
for three days and three nights.
Then I reluctantly
gave him a few words.
Brag as you want.
His Compendium of Swords
was collected in the Arsenal of Liyang.
If you are that good,
you can write one yourself.
I've always been alone.
There are countless ideas in my mind,
but I disdain to write them down.
You are still bragging.
Stop doing it.
I'll keep reading.
Since Senior
said so,
try the Sword Mantra of Killing Whales.
The Sword Mantra of Killing Whales.
Thousands of miles under the sea,
a living beast
rides the tide
with the sound of thunder
and a heart unafraid of the sword.
In spite of the giant waves,
it gets killed
at one slash of the sword.
It's a good idea,
but the mantra is too weak
for such a grand scene.
This book is worse than the last one.
All right.
Let's change another one.
This one.
Jiazi's Sword Practice Records
at Lyushui Pavilion.
It's a swordsmanship brochure
given by Wang Chonglou to me.
It's about the sword techniques.
You haven't mastered Dahuangting.
What's the use of practicing this?
Treatise of the Most Exalted One.
There was something
undefined and complete,
coming into existence
before Heaven and Earth.
How still it was and formless.
The way to use the internal force
resides in the framework of Wudang.
If you want to turn Dahuangting
into your own internal force,
you have to figure out
how to do it yourself.
It makes sense.
Stop reading.
I'll read a different one?
That's it for today.
I just read a few words.
Let me count it.
20.
195 words.
195 pennies.
Smelly old man!
I washed my feet!
You are so talkative!
Otherwise, I could read several books!
You should count how much you owe me!
I don't have any money.
♪ The flower of pain ♪
♪ Blooms in my heart ♪
♪ I made a bet with the dawn ♪
♪ That you'll answer ♪
♪ Forgive this tragic end ♪
♪ Moved by the moment we met ♪
♪ In spite of thunder and lightning ♪
♪ In spite of my falling ♪
♪ When we are apart ♪
♪ I'll collapse ♪
♪ Capture an image of the memory ♪
♪ After all these ups and downs ♪
♪ The vanity ♪
♪ Who will open it again ♪
♪ It's worth it ♪
♪ It's enough ♪
♪ Drowned in sadness ♪
♪ Just to see through ♪
♪ I will whisper love to you ♪
♪ For a lifetime ♪
♪ End the worry in the world ♪
♪ It's worth it ♪
♪ I'll be there for you all my life ♪
♪ After the moments of beauty ♪
♪ You are my reason to be ♪
♪ If there is a way ♪
♪ To start over ♪
♪ Will you still remember me ♪